上溯至宇宙初始 周遭还只是一片漆黑
In the beginning, there was darkness.
不知何时 忽地一声巨响
And then... Bang!
时间空间以及物质皆由此发端
Giving birth to an endless expanding existence
此后不断膨胀 延伸 永无止境
of time, space, and matter.
每一天 新的发现都在不断为我们解开
Every day, new discoveries are unlocking
蕴藏于这里的那些神秘莫测
the mysterious, the mind-blowing,
令人大开眼界 致命的秘密
the deadly secrets of a place we call
我们称这个地方为"宇宙"
the universe.
在深邃虚无的太空
In the deep nothingness of space,
宇宙的沉默被打破
the cosmic silence is broken.
太空其实很嘈杂
Space is actually kind of a noisy place.
星系 恒星 行星和卫星
Galaxies, stars, planets, and moons
高唱着奇异的外域神曲
sing out with strange and alien music.
它们让人以为是外域发来传真
They sound a little bit like an alien fax.
我们将以倒数的形式
Now the cosmic playlist
揭晓宇宙十大金曲
in a top ten countdown,
向大家呈现宇宙最精彩的…
the greatest hits of the universe...
外域声音
in a symphony of alien sounds.
宇宙:外域声音
在太空 无人能听到你的尖叫
In space no one can hear you scream.
作为雷德利·斯科特导演的
As the promo line for Ridley Scott's
科幻电影《异形》的广告词
science-fiction film Alien,
它刻意地让你背脊发凉
it was designed to send chills down your spine.
它基于一个混乱的认识
It's based on the unsettling idea
认为太空是真空的
that space is a vacuum,
声音 无论是尖叫 呼喊 还是唱歌
and sounds, whether screams, shouts, or songs,
都不能在真空里传播
can't travel in a vacuum.
果真如此吗？
But is that really true?
这种想法太狭窄
Well, it's kind of narrow to think that,
不仅在太空里 你听不到任何人的尖叫
in space, you can't hear anyone scream,
而且在地球 也有许多声音我们听不到
because, in fact, here on Earth, there are lots of sounds we can't hear.
它们或是音调太高 或是音调太低
They're either too high a pitch or too low a pitch.
再者 太空不是完全空洞的
Moreover, space isn't completely empty.
最后一点 太空的定义是什么？
And then finally, you know, what's the definition of space?
如果我是在火星表面的宇航员
If I'm an astronaut on the surface of Mars
穿着宇航服的我 是不是在太空里？
and I have a spacesuit on, am I in space, or am I not?
我会认为是
Well, I would think I am.
好的 就这里
Okay, let's try right over here.
说回地球
Back on Earth,
美国加利福尼亚州
Bruce Betts of The Planetary Society
帕萨迪纳行星学会的布鲁斯.贝茨
in Pasadena, California, has given a lot of thought
对火星和声音颇有研究
to Mars and the subject of sound.
他在计算机上编写了
He's programmed his computer
他命名为"火星终结者"的程序
with what he calls the "Marsinator"
去演示在火星寒冷的二氧化碳大气层中
to demonstrate what his voice would sound like in the cold,
在没有宇航服的情况下
carbon-dioxide atmosphere of Mars...
他的声音是怎样的
without those space suits.
火星大气层会改变你的声音
The atmosphere of Mars would actually change your voice
听起来较为低沉
so it sounded deeper.
让我们用"火星终结者"来进行模拟
So let's go ahead and simulate that using the Marsinator,
我会录下我的声音
and I will record my voice,
然后让它变成
and then we will shift it
在火星上听到的声音
to what it would sound like on Mars.
这是我在火星上的声音
This is what I'd sound like on Mars,
我当然希望能有氧气呼吸
although I'd be wishing I had some oxygen to breathe.
然后我通过"火星终结者"对它进行加工
Then I go ahead and process it, put it through the Marsinator.
接着我们回放它 听一听是什么样子
And then we play it back and see what it sounds like.
这是我在火星上的声音
This is how I would sound on Mars,
我当然希望能有氧气呼吸
although I'd be wishing I had some oxygen to breathe.
当然 如果真的有人在火星上这样做
Of course, if humans ever do make it to Mars,
我们不会透过大气层听到他们的声音
we will not hear their voices through the atmosphere.
我们要依赖的是无线电波…
Instead, we'll get them via radio waves...
这种在我们身边萦绕的重要声音
the way many of our most important sounds already reach us.
是
Yes.
我们一想到声音 总是想起
We're familiar with thinking of sound as something
穿过空气来到跟前的东西
that comes through the air to us,
正如谈话时彼此所听到的
just like we hear each other when we're talking,
但实际上 许多我们听到的声音
but, in fact, a lot of the sounds that we hear
是用电磁信号来传送的
are transmitted through electromagnetic signals.
例如 电机是把电视信号
For example, your television actually transmits
转化为声音 让你能听到
a television signal into sound that you can hear.
谁是今晚的第一个选手？
Who's our first contestant tonight?
宇宙里的声音
Sound in the cosmos
永远也不会穿过虚空直达我们这里
will never reach us directly across empty space,
所以无线电 光 或者其它电磁波
so radio, light, or other electromagnetic waves
是必不可少的载体
are the inevitable carriers,
从而让我们能够通过聆听
bringing us a universe we can hear...
去认识宇宙的多样性
in all its variety.
太空其实很嘈杂
Space is actually kind of a noisy place.
它有许许多多的杂音
It has many, many sources of noise
我们能够通过
that we are able to detect
射电望远镜之类的工具去探测它们
with special radio telescopes, for example.
这些外域声音
These alien sounds
构成了一个不可思议的
make up an incredible collection-
超级播放列表
the ultimate playlist.
由天文学家 物理学家组成的专家团
We've polled our expert panel of scientists, astronomers,
投票决出了十个
and physicists to rank the top ten-
来自广袤太空的震憾声音…
the greatest sounds from the expanse of space...
位居榜首的第一名 会让所有人惊讶不已
ending with a number one that will surprise us all.
现在 让我们来倒序欣赏
And now the countdown starts.
第十名是
Coming in at number ten,
跨越130亿光年而来的
ringing out from a distance of 13 billion light-years,
宇宙初生时的婴啼 我们称它为
the birth cry of the universe in a hit called
"大爆炸余音"
"The Audio Afterglow of the Big Bang."
引人注目的是 年幼宇宙曾发出了一个声音
It's remarkable that the young universe actually made a sound,
让我们能够知道
and the reason we know that is that we can actually witness
发光气体在当时已经存在
the glowing gases that were present at that time.
这些气体散发的光
The glow from these gases
被认为是宇宙微波背景辐射
is known as the cosmic microwave background radiation,
即CMBR
or CMBR.
它是一种微弱的微波
It is a faint trace of microwaves
充斥在太空的每个角落
that stretches across every point in the sky.
科学家们在20世纪60年代中期
Discovered by scientists in the mid-1960s,
发现这种辐射是大爆炸的余音
the radiation is the afterglow of the big bang.
著名的"普朗克"CMBR卫星图
The famous Blotchy satellite map of the CMBR
反映了诞生初期
represents the cosmos in its infancy,
只有380 000岁时的宇宙
when it was only 380,000 years old.
我们观察CMBR图
When we look at the CMBR map,
其实是在观察早期宇宙的声纹
we're essentially looking at a voice print of the early universe,
因为这些颜色的微弱变化
because those tiny variations in color
相当于温度的变化
correspond to variations in temperature,
也相当于密度和压力的变化
and those correspond to variations in density and pressure.
受压的波就是声波
Well, pressure waves are just sound waves.
因此 压力的细小变化
So we're seeing little variations in pressure,
就是早期宇宙的细小声波
little sound waves in the early universe.
为透彻理解大爆炸余音
To understand the audio afterglow of the big bang,
我们得去了解早期宇宙
we need to know how the early universe
怎样让压力发生变化 去形成声波
varied its pressures to generate sound waves.
为此 天文学家马克.怀特
To find out, astronomer Mark Whittle
和风琴制作者曼纽尔.罗萨莱斯
and organ builder Manuel Rosales
到加州的克莱尔蒙特联合基督教会
visit the magnificent pipe organ
参观了一架华丽的管风琴
at Claremont United Church of Christ in California.
从某方面来说 这架管风琴的4 000根音管
In a way, the 4,000 pipes in this organ are comparable
所发出的声音堪比早期宇宙的嗓音
to the voice of the early universe.
曼纽尔 早期宇宙让人非常惊讶
Manuel, the amazing thing about the early universe is that
它是万音齐鸣
all its pipes were sounding together,
用这架管风琴来演绎它 应该很好听
and it would be lovely if we could just try that with this organ.
我们同时弹奏出所有音符 好吗？
So do you think we could do that now, play all the notes at once?
好的 尽力而为吧
Yes, let's pull out all the stops and try it.
神曲来啦
Ah, that's where that phrase comes from.
- 好 - 好 动手
- Yes. - Okay, let's go.
非常强劲 只是有点象嘶嘶的白噪声
Very powerful, but really hissy white noise kind of sound,
但宇宙的原始声音有一个非常特别之处
but an even more remarkable thing about the primordial sound
它的音调较为独特
is that, in fact, a few particular tones
而且在任意的时间段内很明显
were present and were stronger at any given time.
这就是首先出场的第十名
This is the opening note of hit number ten,
"大爆炸余音"
"The Audio Afterglow of the Big Bang."
通过计算机的分析 它那明显的音调
A computer sound analyzer reveals its strong tones
在彩色码图中显著不同
as distinct columns on a color-coded graph.
虽然早期宇宙也有嘶嘶声
As hissy as the early cosmic sound is,
但它不同于纯粹的白噪音…
it differs from pure white noise...
白噪音
它在分析仪上毫无规律
which has no organized features at all on the analyzer.
余音
这个"余音" 在另一方面
The sound of the audio afterglow, on the other hand,
让人听起来音色含糊
comes through with a vaguely musical quality.
余音
白噪音
管风琴的音管都由木头和金属制成
The pipes of this, or any organ, are made of wood and metal,
而组成早期宇宙音管的材料是暗物质…
but the pipes of the early universe were pits of dark matter,
只有从重力才能感知其存在的
the mysterious substance whose existence is known
神秘物质
only from its gravity.
声波的载体是重力
What drives the sound waves is gravity.
举例来说 如果某一个区域
So, for example, if there's a region
有稍微高密度的暗物质
of slightly higher density of dark matter,
就会有吸引力
there's a gravitational force pulling in.
周围的气体感受到吸力
Gas that's surrounding this region feels that pull,
就会跑进去
and it falls in.
但它是气体 正如跑进去一样 它会产生压缩
But it's gas, so it also as it falls in, it compresses.
这种压缩就象弹簧
That compression acts like a spring,
推动气体返回出来
and so it pushes the gas back out.
然后它过度膨胀 直到再次跑进去
But then it overshoots until it falls back in again.
气体就是这样运动着 跑进去 弹出来
This is how the motion of the gas falls in, bounces out,
跑进去 弹出来
falls in, bounces out.
所以就产生了一个振荡的压力波 即声波
So we have an oscillating pressure wave, a sound wave.
宇宙背景辐射
The cosmic background radiation,
至关紧要的是 它只是一个静止图像
as important as it is, is just a still picture.
它所反映的声音
Its imprint of sound has the effect
只是嘈杂声 与音乐简直不沾边
of no more than one noisy, barely musical note.
很难听
And even hearing that is a struggle.
管风琴帮我们揭示个中原因
The pipe organ helps show us why.
宇宙的声音远比我们听到的低沉
The sounds of the universe are way too low for us to hear.
这架管风琴的最低音出自哪里？
In fact, what's the lowest note that this organ plays?
出自一根32英尺长的音管
It is a pipe 32 feet long,
只能用脚来弹奏它
and it can only be played with one's foot.
哦 相当低沉
Yeah, that's pretty deep.
对宇宙来说 32英尺的长度等于没有
32 feet were nothing compared to the cosmic organ pipes.
其音管长达20 000至400 000光年
They were between 20,000 and 400,000 light-years across.
对不起 我们没有这么长的音管
Sorry, we don't have any pipes quite that long.
对
No.
早期宇宙的声音如此低沉
The deep sound of the early universe is so low,
我们只有把它变高 才能听得到
we can hear it only after a massive shift upward.
宇宙背景辐射
The background radiation of the universe
始于宇宙诞生后的380 000年
dates from 380,000 years after its creation.
但之前发生了什么呢？
But what happened before that?
可能会发现自大爆炸的那一瞬间起
Is it possible to uncover the whole song of the universe
完整的宇宙之歌吗？
from the very instant of the big bang?
在宇宙响荡着的外域声音中
The cosmos is filled with a symphony of alien sounds,
我们现在欣赏着的是
and we're counting down the top ten
精选出来的第十首
of the universe's greatest hits.
这首"大爆炸余音"
Number ten on the playlist sings out
它唱出了
with the earliest tones of the universe
宇宙最早期之音
from "The Audio Afterglow of the Big Bang."
但是 我们在解读这宇宙婴啼的时候
But our download of the universe's birth song
遇到了一些困难
has some problems.
由于宇宙是同时万音齐奏
With the cosmic organ playing all its pipes at once,
我们耳朵听到的声音
what reaches our ears sounds like
只是一片混乱的嘈杂声
only one complex, noisy note.
它只有一个调 这是因为它是
It's only one note because it comes from the pressure waves
从宇宙背景辐射图解读出来的压力波
we read from the map of the cosmic background radiation,
那只是描绘宇宙诞生380 000年后的
which is just a still picture of the sound in the early universe
早期宇宙声音的静止图像
taken 380,000 years after its birth.
我们怎样去倒流时光
How then do we run the clock backwards
听一听歌曲的其它部分呢？
and hear the rest of the song?
现代天文学相当先进
Modern cosmology is sufficiently advanced
它可以利用计算机
that it's possible to create a computer replication,
模拟幼年期的宇宙
a simulation of the young universe.
能够重现从最初的最初
It's possible to re-create within a computer
到第一个400 000年的这段时间里
what's going on and how the sound developed
发生了什么事
right from the very, very beginning
以及声音如何演变
through those first 400,000 years.
这些超级计算机生动而形象地
They are the same kind of supercomputer simulations
让我们知道了
that have given us pictures
早期宇宙如何发展
showing how the early universe evolved.
早期宇宙的暗物质"音管"
The dark-matter pipes of the early universe
类似于教堂管风琴的音管
acted like those in the church organ.
越大的音管 就会产生越深沉的音调
As bigger pipes were played, deeper notes were sounded.
当宇宙膨胀
As the universe expanded,
空间更大 时间更多
there was more space and more time.
更大的空间意味着更大的音管
More space meant bigger pipes.
所以在演奏的时候
So the notes in the song got lower and lower
曲调越来越低沉
as the song played out.
如果全部算上 那么宇宙最初的400 000年
Put it all together, and the first 400,000 years of the universe
可以被浓缩为一段10秒长的
can be condensed down to just ten seconds-
原始尖叫
a haunting primal scream.
进进出出暗物质区域的气体
The gas that's falling in and out of these dark-matter regions
最后逐渐形成首批星体 首批星河
is ultimately going to become the first stars, the first galaxies,
并最终将会成为我们今天所看到的
and ultimately, it'll be corralled into the thousands of galaxies
无数星河的一部分
that we see around us today.
所以说 重现这些声音 去聆听它们
So while it's been amusing, really, and playful
在好玩 富有乐趣的同时
to reproduce these sounds for us to listen to,
我们要明白
in the big picture,
在未来宇宙和现时宇宙的结构构成中
they play an enormously important role in crafting the structure of the universe
它们都扮演着非常重要的角色
that's going to unfold and the universe that we find ourselves in today.
我们的排行榜倒数
From the big-band sound of the big bang,
从大爆炸的大乐团演奏
our countdown takes a step down in size
转到一个不起眼的一千五百万光年大小的
to the modest 15-million-light-year span
星系团
of a galaxy cluster.
宇宙十大金曲的
Coming in at number nine on our list
第九名是
of the universe's top ten hits
"英仙座沉音"
is the "Deep Tone of Perseus."
这是一个非常低沉的声音
This is low sound to the extreme,
来自于英仙座星系团
emanating from the Perseus cluster,
一个大约有1 000个星系
a grouping of roughly 1,000 galaxies
距离地球25亿光年的地方
250 million light-years from Earth.
这个星团的中心星系
The central galaxy in this cluster of galaxies
其中央有一个特大质量的巨型黑洞
has a huge super-massive black hole at its center.
星团的中心星系称为英仙座A
The cluster's central galaxy is called Perseus A,
它那质量超级大的黑洞 让它成为
and its super-massive black hole gives it what's called
一个活动星系核
an active galactic nucleus,
以排山倒海之势
which shoots out energy in the form of gigantic jets,
猛烈喷射能量到周围空间
tearing into the surrounding space.
由于某些尚未充分了解的原因
For reasons which we don't fully understand,
它看起来象是在喷发
it seems to be coming out.
大约每隔一千万年左右
The energy is being produced episodically
能量会短暂地产生
about every 10 million years or so.
这些能量的波动其实就是压力的波动
Those energy pulses are actually waves of pressure.
而这恰恰正是所谓的声波:
And that's exactly what sound waves are:
压力波
pressure waves.
波 正如体育迷们的展示
The wave, as demonstrated by sports fans,
有着我们非常熟悉的上下往复运动
has an up-and-down motion that's very familiar to us.
但加州大学伯克利分校的学生将会变化一下
But these UC Berkeley students will switch gears
给我们展示声波是如何的不同
and show us how a sound wave is different.
好的 大家放好彩球
Okay, everyone, lose the pom-poms!
由于声波是压力波
Since sound waves are pressure waves,
我们将请学生们制造一个压力波
we're gonna build a pressure wave out of all these students.
好的 大家排成一行
Okay, everybody, let's line up.
肩挨着肩
You go over here and then shoulder-to-shoulder
就象这样
just like this.
一直排下去 不留缺口
Stretch out over there a little bit, no gaps.
你们等一会要互相碰撞
You're gonna be students colliding with each other
就象声波里的分子去互相碰撞
like molecules colliding in a sound wave.
看起来好多了
That's looking a lot better.
你们是一群分子吗？
Do you feel like a bunch of molecules?
- 是 - 好的 不错
- Yeah! - Okay, okay, this is looking good.
队伍两端各有一面大鼓
We have a bass drum at each end of the line.
你等着瞧
You'll see why in a minute.
我们要用鼓来表演
We'll get things going with this drummer over here.
在击鼓之后 请注意发生的事
He's gonna hit the drum, and watch what happens.
在这个例子中 压力很好地传递着
In this case, the pressure is a good healthy shove,
从一个学生到另一个学生
and it moves from student to student
传遍了整个队伍
all the way down the line.
最后 末端的学生通过击鼓
At the end, the last student applies his pressure
把压力传到了第二面鼓
to the second drum by banging on it.
第二面鼓就象是我们的耳膜
This second drum is like our eardrum.
当空气里声波的压力冲击我们的耳膜
When pressure from a sound wave in the air hits our eardrums,
我们就能听到声音
we hear the sound.
正如学生的彼此推动
This is just how sound travels through the air,
空气分子通过彼此推动
except instead of having students shoving each other,
让声音得以穿过空气
there are air molecules shoving each other.
声音需要分子来传送
A sound needs a medium to travel through.
它不能穿越真空
It can't travel through a vacuum.
所以在实际当中 要从A点去到B点
So, in fact, to get from point A to point B,
就需要空气分子彼此碰撞
you need air molecules hitting each other.
这就是它的运作原理
That's how it works.
那么 第九位的"英仙座沉音"
So how do those pressure waves
它的压力波
from number nine's "Deep Tones of Perseus"
是如何穿越星系之间的真空地带呢？
travel through what's essentially the vacuum of intergalactic space?
俄亥俄大学的天体物理学家理查德.波格
Astrophysicist Richard Pogge of Ohio State University
让我们在他学校的足球场上
gives us a sense of the emptiness in deep space
体验太空深处的虚空
at his school's football stadium.
虽然声音真的不能穿越宇宙真空
While it's true that sound waves can't travel through the vacuum of space,
但太空不是完全真空的
space is not a complete vacuum.
这里是俄亥俄体育馆 七叶树队的主场
I'm here at Ohio Stadium, home of the Buckeyes.
今天很空旷 我是唯一的人
It's very empty today. I'm the only one here.
这个场馆能很形象地说明宇宙的真空
And I can't think of a better place to illustrate the vacuum of space.
空空如也的体育馆可以视为
The empty stadium can be a stand-in
宇宙真空的替代物
for the vacuum of space
如果与比赛日的盛况相比较的话
if we compare it with what it looks like on game day.
在超过102 000名观众的情况下
With more than 102,000 people in its seats,
俄亥俄体育馆如同地球的大气层
Ohio Stadium would be like the atmosphere on Earth
空气分子摩肩接踵
jam-packed with air molecules.
要让体育场怎样空荡荡
So how much do we have to clear out this stadium
才相当于宇宙真空呢？
to equal the vacuum of space?
信不信由你 你要赶走每一个人
Believe it or not, you have to clear out everybody,
包括我也不例外
including me, and then even I'm too much.
只有在波格身上的一个细胞也不会留下时
No more than a single cell from Pogge's body
才能让俄亥俄体育馆
could remain in Ohio Stadium
近似于太空深处的真空
to come close to the vacuum of deep space.
在英仙座星系团星系之间
With what seems like almost nothing in the expanse
看似是空无一物
between galaxies of the Perseus cluster,
这让声波的存在更显得不可思议
the existence of sound waves seems all the more incredible.
怎样传送声波 让它穿越极度空洞的太空？
How do you propagate a sound wave through empty space when it's mostly empty?
就以奔跑在赛场上的我作例子吧
Let's use the example of me running down the field.
在遇见别人之前 我不停地跑
I have to run a long ways before I encounter somebody,
遇到别人了
but I still encounter somebody,
我就把能量传递过去
and I can pass energy along to them.
在星际空间里的原子也是如此
The same is true of atoms in interstellar space.
它进行漫漫长征 可能长达300光年
It has to travel a long ways, maybe 300 light-years,
才会遇到另外的微粒
before it encounters another particle,
当彼此相遇 它传递能量
but when it encounters it, it passes the energy,
波就扩散出去
and the wave moves along.
在英仙座星系团里发生碰撞的微粒
The colliding particles in the Perseus cluster
会发射出微弱的X射线
also emit faint X-rays whose traces,
我们利用钱德拉太空望远镜
imaged by the Chandra space telescope,
就能知道波在那里
tell us the waves are there.
但这些波非常多
But these waves are huge,
而且所产生的音调之低
and the notes they produce are lower
是人类从未有遇到过的
than anything any human has ever experienced.
它的音调比我们听到的钢琴中央A音
The pitch is about 57 octaves below our hearing,
要低57个八度
below the middle of a piano range,
这足以让它作为人类知道的最低音调
and that actually qualifies this for the Guinness Book of Records
入选《吉尼斯世界记录》
as the deepest pitch known to man.
这个源自英仙座的极端低音
The extreme deep note emanating from Perseus
远远低于我们的听力范围
is so far below our hearing range
只有在模拟之后 才能听得到
that it can only be approximated.
它被说成是英仙座正在演奏着的
It's been said the galaxy cluster is playing
令人震撼的低音降B曲调
an awesomely low B-flat,
据科学家们的估计
and scientists calculate it'll be playing constantly
它会不停地演奏25亿年
for 2 1/2 billion years.
第九名的"英仙座沉音"
Number nine's "Deep Tone of Perseus"
已经揭开面纱
drones on, as the countdown advances.
虽然神秘的第一名在等着我们
A secret number one waits at the end of the line,
但我们…
but first...
还是按次序看看第八名吧
A strange, high-pitched squeal
这是一个来自宇宙的奇怪尖锐叫声
hints at what comes in at number eight...
它们让人以为是外星人发来的信号
sounds from space and their link to signals from...extraterrestrials.
从大爆炸开始
Starting with the big bang,
我们追寻着宇宙十大金曲…
we've been tracking the top ten of the universe's greatest hits...
这些来自太空的最美妙的外域声音
the best of the alien sounds from space.
现在 让我们见识位居第八的
Jumping to number eight on the countdown,
急速且呈多样化的声音…
we find a sudden wide variety of different sounds...
喀哒声 呜呜声和尖叫声…
clicks, whines, and screeches...
这些我们在银河系里处处能听到的
all coming from strange stars
由奇异星球所唱出的歌声
singing out from everywhere we look in the galaxy.
它们是节奏分明的宇宙之声
They're cosmic squeals with a rhythm section
共同谱写了一曲"韵动脉冲"
in the "Beat of the Pulsars."
每个脉冲星的声音虽然各不相同
Every pulsar has a different sound,
但它们有共同点
but they are all related,
就是会重复信号
because they're repeating blips,
表现出有规律的节奏
beating out regular rhythms.
只是不同声音的
The different sounds come from beats
节拍速度不同
sounding out at different speeds.
一开始 脉冲星发射的无线电波被探测到很有规律
The first pulsars to be detected emitted radio waves so regular
天文学家最初以为这是外星人的信号
that astronomers first thought they were signals from aliens.
但真相很快被揭开
But the truth about them was quickly discovered.
脉冲星是快速转动的中子星
A pulsar is a rapidly rotating neutron star.
其密度非常高
That's a very dense star.
其两极会发射出两束辐射
And it's got two beams of radiation coming out the poles.
当这些辐射旋转并横切过我们的视线
As those beams rotate and intersect our line of sight,
我们就会看到一系列的脉动
we see a series of pulses.
之所以把脉冲星与声音连系在一起
We can think of pulsars being associated with sound,
是因为它们最初是被射电望远镜发现的
because they were first discovered with radio telescopes.
射电望远镜检测到一系列的哔哔声
There was a series of beeps that radio telescopes detected.
一颗缓慢转动的脉冲星
For a slowly rotating pulsar,
你会得到这样的节拍
you might have a series of beats like a metronome...
哔 哔 哔 哔
beep, beep, beep, beep.
PSRB0329脉冲星 每秒1.4转
或者是哔-哔 哔-哔 哔-哔 哔-哔
Or you might hear a beep-beep, beep-beep, beep-beep, beep-beep.
船帆座脉冲星 每秒11转
一颗快速转动的脉冲星
Now, for a rapidly rotating pulsar,
哔哔声混杂在一起 所以会是…
the beeps blur together, so you got...
这样的声音
Like that.
蟹状星云脉冲星 每秒30转
一颗转动非常快速的脉冲星
And for a very rapidly rotating pulsar,
它会是一个连绵的声音
it's just a continuous sound
听起来象是一个音符
that registers like a note in your ears.
J0437脉冲星 每秒176转
脉冲星是巨大质量的恒星坍塌的产物
Pulsars form from the collapse of very massive stars
在恒星发生超新星爆炸后形成
after they explode as supernovas.
一颗质量巨大的恒星
But how long does it actually take
它的坍塌要花多长时间？
for a massive star to collapse?
这是佛罗里达州坦帕市的谢尔曼想知道的…
That's what Sherman D. of Tampa, Florida, wanted to...
宇宙问题
ask the universe,
他为此咨询了我们
when he texted his question to us.
谢尔曼 超新星的影响会持续数月或数年
Sherman, the visible effects of a supernova can last
甚至几个世纪
for months or years or even centuries
如果你去观察超新星遗迹…
if you're looking at the supernova remnant...
这种膨胀气体的话
the expanding gases.
可是 虽然好象是不可思议
But although it may seem incredible,
大质量恒星中心的坍塌
the collapse of the core of a massive star
只不过是一两秒的事
can take just a second or two,
跟着就引发超新星爆炸
and that's what initiates the supernova explosion.
太阳的质量还未大到足以演变为超新星
Our own Sun isn't massive enough to go supernova,
但它是一个巨大的氢球
but it is a giant ball of hydrogen
质量是地球的330 000倍
330,000 times more massive than the Earth
因核聚变而不停燃烧
and burning by nuclear fusion.
所以 正如下一首金曲呈现的那样
So our home star can hardly keep quiet,
我们家园的明星很不安份
as our next hit proves.
第七名是这首热辣的爵士金曲
This hot combo chimes in at number seven on the countdown.
"太阳之歌"
Here it is, the "Song of the Sun."
太阳的声音
The Sun makes sounds,
不可爱
but they're not really sunny sounds.
听起来不好受
They're not happy sounds.
有点象难听的低沉咯咯声
They're kind of low, ominous roars that gurgle along.
太阳之所以发出声音
The Sun makes sounds because there are a bunch of gases
是因为气流串由于对流而忽上忽下
going up and down through a process called convection.
从而产生贯穿太阳这个气体球体的压力波
So they're sending pressure waves through the ball of gas that is the Sun,
让人听起来有点象钟声
and it kind of rings like a bell.
与钟声不同 太阳的声音
Unlike a bell, the Sun rings
同时糅合着一千万种不同的音调
with 10 million different tones at once.
我们从太阳表面压力波的微小鼓胀
We detect them from the tiny bulges
可以检测到它们
from the pressure waves on the Sun's surface.
太阳监测卫星能够对鼓胀高度
Solar satellites measure the height of the bulges
进行十分精确的测量
with exquisite accuracy.
除了声音 它们还带来了科学知识
Apart from sound, they also produce science.
利用观测到的太阳声音
So using these sounds from the Sun that we can observe,
我们能够非常详尽地知道
we can actually tell very detailed things
太阳的内部结构
about the interior structure of our star.
比如 我们能神奇地知道
For example, one of the amazing things that we can tell
什么时候太阳背面有太阳黑子群
is when there's a sun spot group on the other side of the star,
哪怕它还没在边缘出现
even before it comes around the limb
还不能用光学望远镜看到它
and we're able to see it with our optical telescopes.
太阳是太阳系里最大的声音源头
The Sun may be the biggest source for sound in the solar system.
紧跟其后的是木星
But next in line is Jupiter.
它带来了位居第六位的
So coming in at number six in the top ten is a medley
奇怪的电子杂烩"木星爵士乐"
of strange electronic "Jazz from Jupiter."
我们能够知道"木星爵士乐"
"Jazz from Jupiter" comes to us
是因为极其著名的两艘旅行者飞船
courtesy of the two legendary Voyager spacecraft,
它们现在正展开史诗般的旅程 奔向太阳系边界
now on their epic journey to the edge of the solar system.
两艘旅行者飞船
The two Voyager spacecraft
在朝着星际空间飞去
are headed for interstellar space.
它们正处于太阳势力范围的最外边缘
They're on the very outer edges of the bubble the Sun creates around itself.
目前 旅行者1号飞船到太阳的距离
Today Voyager 1 is 118 times
是地日距离的118倍
as far from the Sun as the Earth is,
是海王星到太阳距离的将近四倍
almost four times as far from the Sun as Neptune is.
自从1979年这两艘飞船的
Project scientist Ed Stone has been heading
泛外空间之旅伊始
the Voyager mission since its two spacecraft
工程师ED.斯通一直负责着
made their grand tour of the outer planets
"旅行者任务"
beginning in 1979.
它们在接近木星的时候
On their approach to Jupiter,
首先遇到了一件谁都没想到事
the first thing each one encountered
这个巨星的弓形激波
was the giant planet's bow shock,
从电子信号中传出象风的声音
producing a wind-like sound from the electronic data.
太阳向外吹出的风
There's a wind blowing outward from the Sun
时速约每小时一百万英里
at about a million miles per hour.
超过了音速
It is supersonic.
当风逐渐接触木星周围的磁场
As that wind approaches contact with a magnetic field
它只好降到次音速
around, say, Jupiter, it has to go subsonic.
声激波就会在
There is a sonic shock which forms
木星磁场前面产生
in front of the magnetic field of Jupiter.
它被称为弓形激波
That's called the bow shock.
非常象超音速飞机前面的声激波
It's very much like a sonic shock in front of a supersonic aircraft.
比弓形激波更为有趣的是
More intriguing than the bow shock
木星合唱
is the Jovian chorus,
它恍如拂晓时群鸟的鸣叫声
sounding something like the chorus of birds chirping at dawn.
它和艏波都是来自于木星磁场范围内
Both it and the bow shock come from radio waves
快速运动的带电粒子
generated by fast-moving charged particles
所产生的无线电波
within the bubble of Jupiter's magnetic field.
现在 在向神秘的第一名进发的过程中
Now, the scramble toward the mysterious number one
让我们去聆听
in the top ten
在木星的卫星们与土星环之间响荡着的声音
swings to the moons of Jupiter and the rings of Saturn,
它来自于电回路 发光气体和阵风
where the noises from electric loops, glowing gases, and streams of wind
俨然是太阳系里的
vie for distinction as the spookiest sounds
幽灵声音
in the solar system.
十大宇宙外域声音 现在倒数到了
The top ten countdown in the alien sounds of the universe
木星
has reached Jupiter,
它正向外发送着独具特色的太空音乐
sending out its own brand of space music.
但这首不是独奏曲
But the next hit is no solo.
木星有伴唱团
Jupiter has a backup group.
伴唱者是环绕着这个巨大星球的卫星们
They're the Jovian moons circling the giant planet.
它们各有各唱
And now they have their own album.
十大金曲第五名是
It places at number five in the top ten,
被称为"木卫组曲"的曲子
and the tune is called "Moons Over Jupiter."
领唱的是卫星伽倪墨得斯
The lead singer is the moon Ganymede,
其声音在1995年
recorded by the Galileo spacecraft,
被抵达木星的伽利略航天器录制下来
arriving at Jupiter in late 1995.
伽利略号发回来的
The sounds that Galileo sent back
木卫伽倪墨得斯的声音…
from Jupiter's moon Ganymede...
顺便说一下 它是太阳系最大的卫星…
by the way, the largest moon in the solar system...
非常迷人
are very intriguing.
它们让人以为是外域发来传真
They sound a little bit like an alien fax.
说实在的 当我昨晚在办公室
In fact, when I played that sound clip
播放声音片段时
in my office yesterday,
人们围过来 看看我是不是
people came around the corners to see what was going on,
在接收来自外域的信息
if I was receiving some alien transmission.
与旅行者号一样
As with Voyager,
伽利略号发回的声音出自于电离气体 即等离子
Galileo's sounds came from ionized gas, or plasma.
等离子中的原子分裂为负电子
Atoms in a plasma are split apart into negative electrons
和带正电的原子核
and positive atomic nuclei,
换而言之 即是带电微粒
in other words, charged particles.
航天器上的
Two slender antennas
等离子体波器的两条修长的天线
on the spacecraft's plasma wave instrument
捕获到了
picked up the radio waves
带电微粒因磁场而运动
that the charged particles produced
所产生的无线电波
as they were set in motion by a magnetic field.
这些来自于伽倪墨得斯卫星的声音证明了
These sounds that we hear from Ganymede are the evidence
伽倪墨得斯卫星有一个磁场
that Ganymede actually has a magnetic field,
这得归功于伽利略号上的等离子体波器
and you cannot find that information without using
没有它 我们无法知道这一切
the plasma-wave instrument, as we did on Galileo.
一个突如其来的外域声音
A very sudden burst of alien sound
从木星的另一个卫星传来
came from another of Jupiter's moons.
这发生在伽利略号飞临伊欧的北极上空时
It happened when Galileo flew over Io's north pole.
在太阳系里 我特别喜欢的卫星是木卫一伊欧
My favorite moon in the solar system is Jupiter's moon Io.
它看起来很象比萨饼
It looks a lot like a pizza.
它是整个太阳系里活动最猛烈的卫星
This is the most volcanically active moon in the entire solar system,
比地球的活动猛烈10到100倍
10 or 100 times more volcanically active than the Earth.
它每秒向太空喷发
It literally spews tons of material
数以吨计的
into space every second...
硫磺和氧原子
sulfur and oxygen atoms.
这些物质在木星磁场里成为离子
These get ionized in Jupiter's magnetic field
并反过来影响木星
and actually connect back to Jupiter,
在其南北极产生环状物
to the north and south poles, making a doughnut.
这个环状物被称为木卫一磁流管
The doughnut is called the Io flux tube,
带电粒子在木星和活动猛烈的卫星之间
and the charged particles carry a monster electric current
产生巨大的电流
between Jupiter and its volcanic moon.
在伽利略号穿越它的时候…
As Galileo flew through it...
声音骤然而来 嘎然而止
The sound ended as abruptly as it started.
木星和其卫星的演出告一段落
With Jupiter and its moons finishing their acts,
我们的倒数对象 这次是土星
our countdown swings to Saturn,
它虽比木星小 但也能入围十大金曲榜
smaller than Jupiter but right up there in the top ten.
这个带光环的行星名列第四位
The ringed planet comes in at number four on the list.
请仔细听"土星的超现实声音"
Listen up for the "Surreal Sounds of Saturn."
它们是卡西尼号航天器传给我们的
They come to us from the Cassini spacecraft,
卡西尼号在2004年到达这个行星后
which has been delivering mind-blowing pictures and data
传回了许多令人兴奋的照片和数据
since its arrival at the ringed planet in 2004.
就象旅行者号和伽利略号一样
As on Voyager and Galileo,
卡西尼号的等离子体波器
Cassini's plasma wave instrument is our proxy
充当了我们人类在太空里的耳朵
for human ears in space.
从卡西尼号的无线电和等离子体波器
The eerie and bizarre sounds we hear from
所听到的声音怪诞奇异
Cassini's radio and plasma-wave instrument
让我们犹如置身于万圣节前夕
make me think of Halloween.
它们起源于远比地球极光小得多的土星极光
They're due to the aurora on Saturn, very similar to Earth's aurora.
你的耳朵永远听不出这些频率
Your ears could never pick up these frequencies,
但把它们转换到一定范围后
but we move them into a range, and when we do,
我们会吃惊于它们是多么的怪诞和奇异
we were surprised to see how eerie and scary they actually were.
"土星的超现实声音"
The "Surreal Sounds of Saturn"
不是这个带光环的行星唯一的上榜金曲
isn't the ringed planet's only song on the countdown.
紧接着的金曲榜第三名是
Turn it over, and we find number three on the playlist:
"土星的另一面"
"Saturn's Flip Side."
科学家称这首歌曲为"交叉"
Scientists call this hit a crossover.
这首"交叉"与音乐风格毫无关系
This crossover has nothing to do with mixing musical styles
只是对土星南北半球
but describes radio waves
无线电波波型的描述
from Saturn's northern and southern hemispheres,
它们在一个时间周期内会发生频率交叉
as they actually crisscross in frequency over a period of time.
我们在无线电数据 等离子体波数据中
We saw something really strange in our radio data,
发现相互交叉的一对频率
in our plasma-wave data...
这非常奇怪
a couple of crossing frequencies
似乎暗示着南北半球
that apparently suggested that the northern
在以不同速率旋转
and southern hemispheres were rotating at different rates.
这在我们固体地球上很不寻常
That's very unfamiliar to us on a solid Earth,
地球是以一个速率旋转的
where the Earth rotates at one rate.
不过 我们不认为
It actually turns out we don't think
土星是以不同的速率在旋转
Saturn's rotating at different rates.
我们认为 高空处的西风带蒙骗了我们
We think that high-altitude zonal winds are tricking us
让我们以为南北半球的
and making us think that there's different rotation
旋转速率不同
in the northern and southern hemisphere,
但实情并非如此
but it's probably not the case.
类似的波
Similar waves,
沿着土星磁场路线分布
following the lines of Saturn's magnetic field,
揭露了这个带光环行星的一个神奇现象
revealed a surprise about the ringed planet.
卡西尼号所发现的最离奇事情之一是
One of the most bizarre things that Cassini found
土星的一天
was apparently the Saturn day
比数十年前旅行者号探测到的
was about six minutes longer than it was back in the days of Voyager,
长了6分钟
mere decades earlier.
土星一天的时间长度
The determination of the length of Saturn's day
不能通过观察它周围的云层来测量
is actually not possible by watching the clouds rotate around the planet.
我们只能使用射电辐射这些太空声音
We have to use these radio emissions, the sounds of space,
来观察内部深层的运行情况
to see what the deep interior is doing.
去发现其中奥秘
And that's where we found this mystery.
让土星这样块头的行星
It's virtually impossible to slow down a planet
停滞哪怕一瞬间 那是不可能的
the size of Saturn that much in such a short time.
所以科学家们认识到
So scientists now realize
射电辐射很可能给不出清晰的照片
the radio emissions probably don't give an accurate picture.
靠着对土星风图的精确测绘
And by sophisticated mapping of Saturn's winds,
他们现在已经知道
they now have a better take on Saturn's day,
土星的一天是10小时34分钟13秒
which happens to be 10 hours, 34 minutes, and 13 seconds long.
现在 我们正在接近土卫六泰坦
Now we're closing in on the surface of Titan,
它是土星最大的卫星
Saturn's biggest moon,
也进入了我们的外域声音排行榜
as it swings into the Alien Sounds Countdown.
位居第二的是"非常泰坦"
Hit number two rings out as "Totally Titan."
它以超自然的嘶嘶声作为开始
And it opens with an otherworldly hiss
是卡西尼号在远离地球约十亿英里的地方
from an actual microphone on the Huygens lander,
所释放的惠更斯号登陆车
separated from Cassini
在挂着降落伞穿过泰坦的甲烷大气层时
and parachuting through Titan's methane atmosphere,
车上的麦克风所捕捉到的
nearly a billion miles away from Earth.
在跳伞中 你会听到…
If you're parachuting, you're going to hear...
这正是我们在惠更斯号上听到的声音
That's exactly what we hear in these Huygens sounds.
在2005年 在登陆车冲向泰坦表面的时候
The sound was transmitted as the lander headed
这些声音被传送回来
toward Titan's surface in 2005.
惠更斯号上的声敏元件其实就是麦克风
The acoustic sensor on Huygens was essentially a microphone,
但它是每隔2秒才取样
but it only sampled every couple seconds.
它会短促地捕获声音 细小细小的声音
It would take a little sound tiny, tiny sound bite
接着无声 然后又是细小细小的声音
and then nothing and then a tiny, tiny sound bite.
它没有被计划为普通人听的声音
It wasn't planned to turn that into sounds that the public could hear.
与其它从土星而来的声音不同
But unlike the other sounds from Saturn,
这些并不是转换自无线电波
these were not converted from radio waves.
它们是泰坦甲烷大气层里的真实声波
They began as true sound waves in Titan's methane atmosphere,
行星学会把从麦克风而来的声音样本进行转换
and The Planetary Society stepped in to convert the staccato sampling of the microphone
让人们能听得到
into something audible to human ears.
最后 听到的多半是
In the end, what you hear is mostly wind noise
降落伞穿过大气层时的风噪声
as the parachute's descending through the atmosphere.
然后声音非常非常小
And then things get much, much quieter on the surface.
它从…
It goes from...
突然变成…
To suddenly being...
至关紧要的是 我们听到的声音
But what's really profound is, we're hearing sounds
是由一个十亿英里外的声敏元件
taken by an actual acoustic sensor
所捕捉到的
from a billion miles away.
这是我们首次听到来自于别的行星
First time we've ever heard sounds from another planet
或来自于其卫星的声音
or moon around another planet.
但是 这急速的风声并不是从惠更斯号传来的唯一声音
But the rushing wind wasn't the only sound coming from Huygens.
在登陆车冲向泰坦表面的时候
As data streamed in from the lander on the way to Titan's surface,
控制室里极度紧张的工程师们屏息以待
white-knuckled engineers in Mission Control held their breath,
希望这艘无畏的航天器会安全着陆
hoping the intrepid spacecraft would make its landing safely.
这个故事的最后篇章
The final chapter in the story
是一个不可思议的音乐视频
is told in an incredible music video
保证让你觉得非常刺激
guaranteed to keep you on the edge of your seat.
宇宙十大外域声音
We've been counting down the top ten alien sounds of the universe,
我们已几乎倒数到了第一名
and we've almost reached number one.
但首先 让我们回到第二名
But first we're shifting into high gear...
它有一曲副歌
as number two runs with
其来自于惠更斯航天器
an astronomical riff from the Huygens space probe
当时航天器在拜访土星最大的卫星…
visiting Saturn's largest moon...
泰坦
Titan.
它是唯一一个拥有音乐视频的声音
It's the only alien sound that comes with its own music video.
注意了
Look and listen.
所以说 第二名"非常泰坦"分为两部分
Cut two on number two-it's "Totally Titan."
我们称之为来自于"卡西尼-惠更斯号"的
Here we have what's called the bells and whistles movie
动感电影
from Cassini-Huygens,
它展示了下降的过程
and it's showing the descent,
是利用声音去传递各种不同数据的
and it's a great example of using sound
一个极好例子
to convey all sorts of different kinds of data.
正如盖格计数器
Just as a Geiger counter
用听得到的喀哒声来报告放射性
announces radioactivity using audible clicks,
在惠更斯登陆车上的仪器也会发出声音
the instruments on the Huygens lander were given their own sounds
来表明自己的状态
to register the measurements they were taking.
你听到的韵律声 每一下都意味着
Those chimes you hear each one of those means
仪器或是正在照相
that an instrument was taking a picture
或是在捕获其它数据
or some other kind of data.
不同的仪器有不同的声响
Different instruments are a different chime.
我们也会听到背景杂音
We also are hearing a kind of a hum in the background.
那是因为在与卡西尼号通信
That's the signal strength to the Cassini spacecraft.
我们发现 有一个嘀嘀声一闪而过
We've got a ticking that occurs
这与航天器的旋转有关
that has to do with the spinning and rotation of the spacecraft.
每旋转一次 就会有这个嘀嘀声
Every time it rotates once, they have the tick.
虽然这是科学仪器的大合唱
Though it's just an assembly of pure scientific information,
这个视频似乎在原汁原味地展现
the video seems to preserve what must have been
扣人心弦的最后时刻…
those last moments of high tension...
任务控制室内的科学家们想知道
when the scientists in Mission Control wondered,
"这个小不点航天器会安全着陆"
"Will the tiny spacecraft land safely,
"还是会撞毁？"
or will it crash?"
开始啦 差不多了…
So here we go, and almost down...
然后…
and then...
着陆了
and we're landed.
在十亿英里外的一片声响中…
Mission accomplished...
任务完成了
with sound a billion miles away.
第二名的"非常泰坦"
"Totally Titan" has been a thrill
让我们激动万分
at number two on the countdown,
现在 让我们在唱片机上播放神秘的第一名…
but now we spin the platter on the mysterious number one...
这首歌曲的发源地
A song that comes from a place totally unlike
在我们所认识的宇宙中 与别处绝然不同
anything else in the universe we've ever encountered.
正如从木星和土星而来的信号
While some remind us of the strange signals from Jupiter and Saturn,
这首歌曲的声音也让我们奇怪之至
there are also sounds in this song
它完全不同于我们曾测量过的东西
that are completely different from anything we've measured
也不同于我们在宇宙其它地方曾发现的东西…
or detected anywhere else in the cosmos...
这是因为第一名
because number one on the countdown
虽在外面的整个宇宙里回响
has sounds alien to the entire universe,
但偏偏把它的发源地排除在外
except for the place where they originate.
宇宙金曲的第一名
Number one in the universe's greatest hits
是一个特别地方的回响
resounds with echoes of a singular place.
它就是"地球回声"
"The Echoes of Earth."
在地球 我们习惯地认为
Here on Earth, we're used to thinking of the alien sounds
外域声音是来自于我们星球之外
as being everything that comes from beyond our planet,
它应当象穿透天文物理介质或物体的
and that might be examples of plasma waves
等离子波和压力这些东西
and pressure moving through astrophysical media or objects.
但实际上 如果你从远方观察我们的地球
But, really, if you think about observing our Earth from afar,
外星人就是我们
the aliens are us.
我们的声音独一无二
And our sounds are unique,
因为它来自于活着的生物
because they come from living organisms,
它是人类的语言…
whether it be human language...
或是鸟儿的歌
Or bird songs.
外域探测器扫描地球表面时
An alien probe exploring Earth space
肯定会捕获到与木星或土星相类似的
would certainly pick up the Jupiter or Saturn-like sounds
带电粒子因被地球磁场推动而产生的声音
of charged particles propelled by Earth's magnetic field.
但我们的行星 与众不同的是
But our planet, unlike the others,
还会发出无线电波
also emits radio waves,
在宇宙里昭告人类的存在
broadcast into the cosmos by human beings.
晚上好 我是雷吉纳德 A. 费森登教授
Good evening, this is Professor Reginald A. Fessenden,
在马萨诸塞州的布兰特洛克镇和你说话
speaking to you from Brant Rock, Massachusetts.
1906年 在马萨诸塞州的布兰特洛克镇
In 1906, at Brant Rock, Massachusetts,
雷吉纳德.费森登首次利用无线电
Reginald Fessenden made the first radio broadcast
广播了声乐节目
of speech and music.
费森登是调幅(AM)广播的发明者
Fessenden was the inventor of AM radio,
他在圣诞前夕进行了首次信号传送
transmitting his first signals on Christmas Eve.
信号被水手们在数百英里外的海洋上捕捉到
It was picked up by sailors hundreds of miles out at sea
并从此贯穿太空
and has been traveling through space ever since.
自从有了无线电
Ever since the beginning of radio,
我们一直在向太空发出广播
we've really been broadcasting out into space.
我们所发送的这些信号
And we've been sending out these signals,
希望有某些人会截获到
in the hopes that somebody will intercept them.
当然 太空实在太大了
Of course, space is a very large place,
所以 难以知道
and, therefore, it's hard to know
谁会在什么时候收到它们
who would have gotten them and when,
但他们会在那里 尽管谁也不知道是哪里
but there they are on their way out to who knows where.
地球上的小孩在向您打招呼
Hello from the children of Planet Earth.
(日语)
地球上的声音也在太空里传送着
Earthly sounds are also traveling through space,
但靠的不是无线电 而是装载在稳步迈向太空深处的…
not by radio, but aboard the two Voyager space probes...
两艘旅行者号上的探测仪
on a slow but steady course to the stars.
大家早上好
Bonjour, tout le monde.
对地球上的我们来说 声音很重要
One of the examples of how important sound is
所以 在发射旅行者号的时候
to us here on Earth is that when we launched Voyager,
我们放上了一张录有地球声音的黄金唱片
we actually included a golden record of sounds from our Earth.
其中不仅有人类的声音
And this was to represent not only human sound
还有许多同在地球生活的生物的声音
but also sounds of the many creatures that live here on Earth with us.
所以 它实际上是地球生命的声学指纹
So it's really a sound fingerprint of life on our planet.
我们以自己的方式
As we take our own place
对十大声音进行的探讨
among the top ten hits in our playlist,
对响荡在虚空里的太空声音来说
we realize they only scratch the surface
其实很肤浅
of the cosmic voices calling out in the void.
从创世至今
From creation to the present day,
宇宙产生了数不胜数的声音
space has produced a broad catalog of sounds
为它的壮丽景色伴奏
to accompany its brilliant sights.
这些各种各样的声音似乎很怪异
As strange as these many sounds seem,
但我们知道 它们携带着重要信息
we've learned that they carry important messages,
能帮助我们去解开自然之谜
helping to solve mysteries of nature
让我们最大程度地去了解宇宙
and our ultimate understanding of the universe.